Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Creative Department Commercial Scripts, 1954-1982 RL.11167
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Creative Department Commercial Scripts
1955-1982
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11167
7.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Collection consists of scripts to television commercials for sponsored television programming.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically. Collection is minimally processed; original folders and titles were retained.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Creative Department Commercial Scripts were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1990.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following J. Walter Thompson Company Archives collections held in the Hartman Center: Account Files; Granger Tripp papers; Radio and Television Department records.
Collection Overview
Consists of scripts to television commercials for sponsored television programming. Companies represented include Aluminum Limited and Kodak. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Television advertising; J. Walter Thompson Company; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- Aluminum Limited, 1954-1964; 1
  - TV commercials, 1954-1964 (Box 1)
- Kodak commercial scripts, 1955-1982; 2
  - Academy Awards, 1966-1969 (Box 1)
  - Academy Awards, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Ed Sullivan Show, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
  - Ed Sullivan Show, 1959-1960 (Box 3)
  - Ed Sullivan Show, 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Ed Sullivan Show, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Norby 1955; Screen Directors' Playhouse 1955; Ozzie Harriett 1956, 1955-1956 (Box 5)
  - Ozzie Harriett, 1957-1960 (Box 6)
  - Scripts, 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - Scripts, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Scripts, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - Scripts, 1969-1971 (Box 10)
  - Scripts, 1972-1975 (Box 11)
  - Scripts, 1976-1982 (Box 12)